<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Brief Discussion of Machine Learning in Condensed Matter Physics and Computational Material Science</title>
    <link href="/2022/01/07/6/"/>
    <url>/2022/01/07/6/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Brief-Discussion-of-Machine-Learning-in-Condensed-Matter-Physics-and-Computational-Material-Science"><a href="#Brief-Discussion-of-Machine-Learning-in-Condensed-Matter-Physics-and-Computational-Material-Science" class="headerlink" title="Brief Discussion of Machine Learning in Condensed Matter Physics and Computational Material Science"></a>Brief Discussion of Machine Learning in Condensed Matter Physics and Computational Material Science</h2>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>How to Become a Qualified Wannierizer?</title>
    <link href="/2021/12/06/2/"/>
    <url>/2021/12/06/2/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="How-to-Become-a-Qualified-Wannierizer"><a href="#How-to-Become-a-Qualified-Wannierizer" class="headerlink" title="How to Become a Qualified Wannierizer?"></a>How to Become a Qualified Wannierizer?</h2><p>Maximally-localized Wannier functions.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Efficient Ab initio Method for Calculations of Electron-Defect Scattering</title>
    <link href="/2021/12/05/1/"/>
    <url>/2021/12/05/1/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Efficient-Ab-initio-Method-for-Calculations-of-Electron-Defect-Scattering"><a href="#Efficient-Ab-initio-Method-for-Calculations-of-Electron-Defect-Scattering" class="headerlink" title="Efficient Ab initio Method for Calculations of Electron-Defect Scattering"></a>Efficient <em>Ab initio</em> Method for Calculations of Electron-Defect Scattering</h2><h2 id="Introduction"><a href="#Introduction" class="headerlink" title="Introduction"></a>Introduction</h2><p>As is known to all, electron-phonon interactions govern charge carriers dynamics at room temperature, where they play intrinsic roles in limiting carrier mobility.On the other hand, just like phonons, defects in materials can also scatter or capture charge carriers. They become significant for carrier dynamics at low temperature,where phonons are frozen out.</p><p>However, first-principle calculations of electron-defect interactions are still in their infancy. Those calculations need large supercells to obtain the electron wave function and defect perturbation potentials, which may lead huge computational cost. Here, I’d like to introduce a more efficient scheme to compute the electron-defect scattering matrix elements. This approach is firstly proposed by Bernardi’s group at Caltech, and it dose not require the wave functions of large supercells, which dramatically accelerates the calculations.</p><h2 id="Methodology"><a href="#Methodology" class="headerlink" title="Methodology"></a>Methodology</h2><p>The electron-defect scattering matrix elements $M_{n^{\prime} k^{\prime} , nk}$ encode the probability amplitude from the unperturbed state $|nk\rangle$ to $|n^\prime k^\prime \rangle$ due to the perturbation potential $\Delta V_{e-d}$ from a defect:<br>$$<br>M_{n^{\prime} k^{\prime} , nk} = \langle n^\prime k^\prime | \Delta V_{e-d} | nk\rangle<br>$$</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Optimizing Contraction order of the Tensor Network Generated from Google Sycamore Quantum Circuit</title>
    <link href="/2021/12/04/5/"/>
    <url>/2021/12/04/5/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Optimizing-Contraction-order-of-the-Tensor-Network-Generated-from-Google-Sycamore-Quantum-Circuit"><a href="#Optimizing-Contraction-order-of-the-Tensor-Network-Generated-from-Google-Sycamore-Quantum-Circuit" class="headerlink" title="Optimizing Contraction order of the Tensor Network Generated from Google Sycamore Quantum Circuit"></a>Optimizing Contraction order of the Tensor Network Generated from Google Sycamore Quantum Circuit</h2>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Topological Phase Transition in Two-dimensional skyrmion materials</title>
    <link href="/2021/12/03/3/"/>
    <url>/2021/12/03/3/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Topological-Phase-Transition-in-Two-dimensional-skyrmion-materials"><a href="#Topological-Phase-Transition-in-Two-dimensional-skyrmion-materials" class="headerlink" title="Topological Phase Transition in Two-dimensional skyrmion materials"></a>Topological Phase Transition in Two-dimensional skyrmion materials</h2>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Valleytronics in Two-dimensional systems</title>
    <link href="/2021/12/02/4/"/>
    <url>/2021/12/02/4/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Valleytronics-in-Two-dimensional-systems"><a href="#Valleytronics-in-Two-dimensional-systems" class="headerlink" title="Valleytronics in Two-dimensional systems"></a>Valleytronics in Two-dimensional systems</h2><h2 id="Valley"><a href="#Valley" class="headerlink" title="Valley"></a>Valley</h2><p>In analogy to charge for electronics and spin for spintronics, valley, as a new degree of freedom for electrons, can be utilized to encode and process information, which is characterized as Valleytronics and has drawn considerable attention due to its significant potential for developing next-generation minimized devices.</p><p>The valley refers to a local energy minimum (maximum) in conduction (valence) band at the K and K’ points in the first Brillouin Zone, which is robust against phonon and defect scatterings due to the large separation in the momentum space. Therefore, two-dimensional materials with hexagonal lattice should be the most competitive candidates to be applied in valleytronic devices.</p><img src="/img/valley1.png" width="95%" height="95%"><h2 id="Valley-polarization"><a href="#Valley-polarization" class="headerlink" title="Valley polarization"></a>Valley polarization</h2><p>In order to distinguish non-equivalent valleys, the major challenage in two-dimensional valley materials is  to break the degeneracy between the valleys, thus forming the valley polarization, which opens a window for capturing the valley degree of freedom and is indispensable for valleytronic applications. The degeneracy between valleys results in the protections of inversion symmetry and time-reversal symmetry. Therefore, monolayers of 2H-phase transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs) are the most promising candidates for valley polarization, since the inversion symmetry for their structures is explicitly broken, and noncentrosymmetry together with intrinsic spin-orbit coupling (SOC) derived from the <em>d</em> orbitals of heavy transition metals lead spin and valley degree of freedom couple strongly. As a result, in TMDs monolayers, it is very fundamental and effective to introduce an external magnetic field to break the time-reversal symmetry and induce valley splitting. Unfortunately, the extreme field strength for a sizable valley splitting is not accessible in practice use. To explore intrinsic valley polarization in TMDs is thus highly desirable.</p><img src="/img/valley2.png" width="95%" height="95%"><h2 id="Ferrovalley-property"><a href="#Ferrovalley-property" class="headerlink" title="Ferrovalley property"></a>Ferrovalley property</h2><p>In analogy to ferroelectric materials with spontaneous charge polarization, or ferromagnetic materials with spontaneous spin polarization, here we introduce a new member of ferroic family, that is, a ferrovalley material with spontaneous valley polarization.</p><p>we rebuild the Hamiltonian for the classical monolayers of TMDs, and point out that the coexistence of the SOC effect and exchange interaction of localized d electrons is the sufficient condition for spontaneous valley polarization in this kind of systems.</p><p>In order to break the time-reversal symmetry and induce the valley polarization, additional term $H_{ex}(k)$ is introduced into the effective Hamiltonian.</p><img src="/img/eq1.png" width="95%" height="95%"><p>The first term with up to second-nearest-neighbour hopping is given by:</p><img src="/img/eq2.png" width="95%" height="95%"><p>The second term describes the SOC:</p><img src="/img/eq3.png" width="95%" height="95%"><p>The last and most crucial term originates from the intrinsic exchange interaction of transition-metal <em>d</em> electrons:</p><img src="/img/eq4.png" width="95%" height="95%"><p>where the $\sigma_z$ is the Pauli matrix and $m_u (m_l)$ represents the spliting energy in the band edge of UB(LB)</p><p>The exchange interaction, equivalent to an intrinsic magnetic field, tends to split the spin-majority and spin-minority states. Combining the SOC effect that leads to coupled spin and valley indexes with the valley-independent exchange interaction, the valley polarization is therefore feasible.</p><img src="/img/valley3.png" width="95%" height="95%"><p>Numerical result by QuTip is shown above. The codes can be accessed via my <a href="https://nbviewer.org/github/grj-skyline/littleproj/blob/main/Ferrovalley.ipynb"><font color=DeepSkyBlue>jupyter notebook viewer</font></a>.</p><h2 id="Perspective-from-electron-mobility"><a href="#Perspective-from-electron-mobility" class="headerlink" title="Perspective (from electron mobility)"></a>Perspective (from electron mobility)</h2>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Welcome to my personal website</title>
    <link href="/2021/11/04/hello/"/>
    <url>/2021/11/04/hello/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Welcome-to-my-personal-website"><a href="#Welcome-to-my-personal-website" class="headerlink" title="Welcome to my personal website!"></a>Welcome to my personal website!</h2>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
